

Website: <a href="https://http

Austin, TX

(347) 831-6041 hanafrla@utexas.edu

Profile

PhD Student at University of Texas at Austin and Research Associate at Carnegie Mellon University.

Interested in researching social aspects of modern technology to create a better future, specifically in the context of open source software communities and participation.

Education

University of Texas at Austin; Austin, TX

08/2021 - Present

Currently pursuing a doctoral degree in Information Studies

- Faculty Advisor: Professor James Howison

Carnegie Mellon University; Pittsburgh, PA

08/2016 - 05/2020

B.Sc. Electrical and Computer EngineeringMinor in Human-Computer Interaction

Research Experience

Research Associate; Human-Computer Interaction Institute*, CMU

05/2020 - Present

*In conjunction with the Institute for Software Research.

- Currently at the CoEx Lab under professors Dr. Laura Dabbish and Dr. James Herbsleb.
 - Designing bot interventions on Github seeking to aid first-time contributors
 - Analyzing the unique experiences of BIPOC and trans, non-binary, and genderqueer folk in open source communities
 - Studying the maintainer and organizational influence on project diversity and newcomer retention
 - Analyzing Github conversations regarding codes of conduct and governance

Research Assistant; Human-Computer Interaction Institute, CMU

09/2019 - 05/2020

- An empirical qualitative study analyzing diversity and inclusion in open source.
- Screened 4000+ users, recruited and interviewed 21 participants, created a coding scheme following grounded theory, and first-authored a paper currently under review.

Research Assistant; Institute for Software Research, CMU

09/2018 - 05/2019

Project validated a new fault-injection framework by retrofitting existing open source applications, developing models of expected application results, and creating a general server in Erlang within Partisan protocol to accomplish hierarchical clustering.

Research Assistant; Electrical and Computer Engineering, CMU

05/2018 - 08/2018

Project involved building and programming a wireless system for neural recording, capable of streaming digitized data to a remote machine for analysis. Project required system design, PCB sketching and milling, and embedded systems application.

Publications

Li, Renee, Pavitthra Pandurangan, **Hana Frluckaj**, and Laura Dabbish. "Code of Conduct Conversations in Open Source Software Projects on Github." *Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction* 5, no. CSCW1 (2021): 1-31.

(Major Revision) Hana Frluckaj, Laura Dabbish, David Gray Widder, James D. Herbsleb "Gender and Participation in Open Source Software Development" In: Conference on Computer-supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW)

Papers in progress

Hana Frluckaj, Huilian Qiu, Laura Dabbish, Bogdan Vasilescu, "Trickle Down Diversity: Company Influence on open source project diversity"

Working Experience

IT Assistant, Institute for Software Research; *Pittsburgh, PA*09/2016 - 05/2020

Performed diagnostics and initial troubleshooting tasks, investigated hardware and software issues, and assisted 120+ students, staff, and faculty with technological needs.

Technology Analyst, Deutsche Bank; New York, NY

06/2019 - 08/2019

Built a simulator for messages sent between international credit/debit tracking systems in Java using Spring environment. In parallel, built and presented a sentiment analysis application focusing on public traded companies, their stocks, and media bias in Python using ML and NLP. Advocated for increased diversity in presentations and discussions.

Engineering Aide, Consolidated Edison, Inc.; New York, NY

07/2015 - 08/2017

- 05/2017 08/2017: Built test scripts and aided IT programmers in identifying algorithmic fallacies in OBIEE Performance Manager within Public Engineering.
- 09/2015 07/2016: Reviewed data filing for over 4000 work requests, organized data lists of employee review calls, and maintained documentation of ConEd facilities.
- 07/2015 09/2015: Reviewed conflicts of the energy grid, worked with external agencies, and compiled estimate cost data in Excel.

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, C/C++, Processing, Verilog, Java, Erlang, Go, and Matlab **Technical:** Unix/Linux, Computer Security, Computer Systems, Sentiment Analysis, Digital Signal Processing, Test-Driven Development, User Experience Design, Human-Robot Interaction, and Computer Graphics

Research: Github repository mining, qualitative analysis, Grounded Theory, recruitment, interviewing, transcription, affinity diagrams, and literature reviews

Spoken Languages: English (Native), Serbo-Croatian (Native), French (Working)

Institutional Service

iSchool Diversity and Inclusion Committee SIGBOVIK 2021 - Moderation Chair WiCyS 2019 - Student Volunteer 08/2021 - Present

Students Mentored

Magali Astride Ngouabou Noubissi, student at Pomona University

06/2020 - Present

	Raaka Mukhopadhyay, student at Carnegie Mellon University.	01/2021 - 05/2021
Organizations	International Student Union; CMU Held the positions of President, Treasurer, and Secretary.	02/2017 - 05/2020
	Women in ECE; CMU	09/2016 - 05/2020
	Society of Women Engineers; CMU	09/2016 - 05/2020
	Girls Who Code; Brooklyn Technical High School	09/2015 - 08/2016
	Held the position of Mentor.	
References	Associate Professor Laura Dabbish: dabbish@cmu.edu	
	Professor James Herbsleb: jdh@cs.cmu.edu	
	Assistant Professor Bodgan Vasilescu: vasilescu@cmu.edu	